Guide to the Vassar College Assistant to the President Records, 1929-1979
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Assistant to the President Records,
1929-1979
Vassar College. Assistant to the President
32 cubic feet (32 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Office files containing correspondence, minutes, memoranda, calendars, and questionnaires relating to students, endowments, lecture series, committees, and other college business.
Administrative History
The first Assistant to the President, Arthur A. Hauck, was hired in 1929. The position was originally requested by the Trustee's Endowment Committee, with the purpose of bringing financial expertise to the administration in order to handle the burgeoning numbers of gifts and bequests. The position has changed to meet the needs of subsequent administrations to include a variety of functions.
Scope and Content Note
Office files containing correspondence, minutes, memoranda, calendars, and questionnaires relating to students, endowments, lecture series, committees, and other college business. The records were created and maintained by either an Assistant to the President or the President's Executive Secretary.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Endowments; Vassar College. Library
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
VCL Categories
Vassar College Presidents
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, April 2007.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from the Office of the President.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 7 series. Each series includes the records of a particular Assistant to the President or Executive Secretary.
Container List
- Arthur A. Hauck
  - Card file, ca. 1920-1938 (Box 1)
- Sydnor H. Walker
  - A-E, 1938-1952 (Box 1)
  - E-P, 1938-1952 (Box 2)
  - P-Z, 1938-1952 (Box 3)
  - Academic Invitations, 1949/1950-1955/1956 (Box 3)
  - Calendar, 1950/1951-1952/1953 (Box 3)
  - "Displaced Persons" — Students who never came (Box 3)
  - Endowment Committee, 1950-1953 (Box 3)
  - International Relations Committee (Box 3)
  - Kenyon Lectures, 1949-1953 (Box 4)
  - Lecture Committee, 1950-1952 (Box 4)
  - Library Committee, 1950-1952 (Box 4)
  - Middle East Seminar (Box 4)
  - Student Questionaires to 1954 (Box 4)
- Florence Clothier Wislocki
  - A, ca. 1956-1968 (Box 4)
  - A-C, ca. 1956-1968 (Box 5)
  - C-H, ca. 1956-1968 (Box 6)
  - I-T, ca. 1956-1968 (Box 7)
  - U-Z, ca. 1956-1968 (Box 8)
  - Trustees, ca. 1956-1968 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, including Mellon Conference, Commencements, 1949-1970; (box only 3/4 full) (Box 8)
- George Langdon / Glenn Johnson
  - Group 1, 1967-1970 (Box 10)
  - Group 2, 1967-1970 (Boxes 10-11)
  - Group 3, 1968-1969 (Boxes 11-12)
  - Group 4, 1968-1970 (Boxes 12-13)
  - Group 5, 1968-1970 (Boxes 13-14)
  - Group 6, 1968-1971 (Boxes 14-15)
  - Group 7, 1968-1972 (Boxes 15-17)
  - Group 8, 1968-1972 (Boxes 17-18)
  - Group 9, 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - Group 10, 1971-1972 (Box 20)
  - Misc. Additions, (box less than 1/4 full) (Box 21)
- Velma Gooding
  - Date Books, 1959-1976 (Box 9)
  - Gooding, 1968-1973 (Boxes 22-23)
- Gregory Fahlund
  - Group 1, 1971-1973 (Boxes 23-24)
  - Group 2, 1973-1976 (Box 24)
  - Group 3, 1971-1976 (Boxes 25-26)
  - Group 4, 1972-1974 (Boxes 26-27)
  - Group 5, 1973-1975 (Boxes 28-29)
- Marla Orr MacKenzie
  - A-C, 1973-1977 (bulk 1975-1977) (Box 29)
  - C-Z, 1973-1977 (bulk 1975-1977) (Box 30)
  - A-C, 1971-1979 (bulk 1977-1979) (Box 30)
  - C-Z, 1971-1979 (bulk 1977-1979) (Box 31)
  - Trustees, 1975-1979; (Box 32 only 1/4 full) (Boxes 31-32)